rewarder.com 2014-06-26

# 

**Privacy Policy**

Effective Date: January 27, 2014

Rewarder, Inc. ("Rewarder") values your privacy. Rewarder is a marketplace for knowledge. At rewarder.com and on Rewarder's mobile application ("App"), users can offer a monetary reward ("Reward") in exchange for knowledge or expertise from real people. Our 750,000+ experts compete to receive Rewards by offering the best help. In this Privacy Policy ("Policy"), we describe how we collect, use, and disclose information that we obtain about visitors to our website rewarder.com (the "Site"), users of our App and the services available through our Site and App (collectively, the "Services").

By visiting the Site, using or downloading the App, or using any of our Services, you agree that your personal information will be handled as described in this Policy. Your use of our Site or Services, and any dispute over privacy, is subject to this Policy and our Terms of Use, including its applicable limitations on damages and the resolution of disputes. Rewarder's Terms of Use are available at [www.rewarder.com/terms](https://www.rewarder.com/terms) and are incorporated by reference into this Policy.

Rewarder, Inc. has received TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy statement and our practices have been reviewed for compliance with the TRUSTe program viewable on the validation page available by clicking the TRUSTe seal. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site, http://rewarder.com and does not cover information that may be collected through our mobile applications.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact TRUSTe [_here_](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request).

The Information We Collect  
How We Use the Information We Collect  
How We Share Your Information  
Our Use of Cookies and Other Tracking Mechanisms  
Third-Party Analytics  
User-Generated Content  
Third-Party Links  
Security of My Personal Information  
Access to My Personal Information  
Marketing Communications  
Children Under 13  
Changes to this Policy  
Contact Us  

**The Information We Collect**

We may collect information about you directly from you and from third parties, as well as automatically through your use of our Site, App, or Services.

**_Information We Collect Directly From You._**

  * _Registration Information._  In order to post questions and Rewards or to post an answer to a question, you must, register for an account with us. To register for an account through our Site or App, you may be able to log in with your login information for select social networking sites (including Facebook, Twitter, Google+), or you may register directly with us, in which case you must provide your name and email address. We may also collect optional information from you, such as your mobile phone number a photo, your date of birth, and additional profile information (such as your areas of expertise).
  * _Purchase and Payment Information._  If you make a purchase, we will collect your credit or debit card information, your billing and shipping address, and other information to process your payment and confirm your identity. You are required to provide us with this information.

**_Information that We Collect About You from Social Networking Sites._** As noted, you also may log into our Site and App through your Facebook, Twitter, and Google+. If you do this, you must authenticate yourself as a registered user of that site, and will be asked to grant us permission to access certain information from your account with that site, as follows:

  * _Facebook_. To log in to our Site or App through Facebook Connect, you must grant us permission to: (i) access and collect your Facebook basic information (includes your name, profile picture, gender, networks, list of friends, date of birth, email address, and any other information you have set to public on your Facebook account); (ii) post to your Wall; (iii) access posts in your newsfeed, and (iv) and access any other information listed on the permissions page when you connect using your account. If you allow us to have access to this information, then we will have access to this information even if you have chosen not to make that information public.
  * _Twitter_. To log in to our Site or App through Twitter, you must give us your Twitter registered email address, and permission to read Tweets from your timeline and see whom you follow.
  * _Google+_. To log in to our Site or App through Google+, you must grant us access to your Google+ email address, Google+ profile information, and other information listed on the permissions page when you connect using your account.

We store the information that we receive from these sites with other information that we collect from you or receive about you. Any third-party social networking site controls the information it collects from you. For information about they may use and disclose your information, including any information you make public, please consult their respective privacy policies. We have no control over how any third-party site uses or discloses the personal information it collects about you.

**_Information We Collect Automatically._** We may automatically collect the following information about your use of our Site and App through cookies, web beacons, java script, and other technologies: your domain name; your browser type; your operating system; your device type; pages you view; links you click; your IP address; data and time you access our Site or App; the length of time you use our Site or App; your activities on our Site or App; language information; device or other identifier; location information; and the referring URL, or the webpage that led you to our Site. We may combine this information with other information that we have collected about you, including, where applicable, your user name, name, and other personal information. Please see the section Our Use of Cookies and Other Tracking Mechanisms below for more information.

**How We Use the Information We Collect**

We use the information that we gather about you for the following purposes:

  * To provide our Services to you, to communicate with you about your use of our Services, to respond to your inquiries, to fulfill your orders, and for other customer service purposes.
  * To tailor the content and information that we may send or display to you, to offer location customization and personalized help and instructions, and to otherwise personalize your experiences while using our Site, App, or Services.
  * Where you have asked us to, to send you text notifications about the status of Rewards you have posted or responded to.
  * For marketing and promotional purposes. For example, we may email you news and newsletters, special offers, and promotions about third party products or services we think may interest you, or information about Rewards we think may interest you. We also may use the information that we learn about you to assist us in advertising our Services on third-party websites. 
  * To better understand how users access and use our Site, App, and Services, both on an aggregated and individualized basis, in order to improve our Site, App, and Services; respond to user desires and preferences; and for other research and analytical purposes.
  * To post to your Facebook Wall, if you have granted us permission to do so.

**How We Share Your Information**

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. We do not sell your personal information to third parties. We may share the information that we collect about you as follows:

  * **_Rewarder Users._** Your name, user name (including if you have signed in using a social networking account), photo and the profile information you create with us, as well as any information that you post to our Site and App, including Rewards, reviews, comments, and text will be available to, and searchable by, all users of the Site, App, and Services and by non-registered visitors to our Site.
  * **_Facebook and other Social Networking Users._** Your username and profile picture will be visible to all other Rewarder users, regardless of whether they are your friends, followers or contacts. In addition, when you join Rewarder, if you grant us permission to post on your Facebook Wall, a notification will be visible on your Facebook page telling your friends that you have started using Rewarder. Our App also will be visible on your Facebook page under "applications."
  * **_Service Providers._** We may disclose the information we collect from you to third-party vendors, service providers, contractors, or agents who perform functions on our behalf, including those who process or facilitate payments from our users. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.
  * **_Business Partners._** We may also share information about the Rewards you have posted, as well as you public profile information, with select business partners who may use your information for their own purposes. We do not share your email or other contact information with these partners; however, they may have access to your email address, contact and information from other sources and may combine the information we give them with the other information they have collected about you. If you do not want us to share your personal information with these companies, contact us at [info@rewarder.com](mailto:info@rewarder.com).
  * **_Business Transfers._** If we are acquired by or merged with another company, if substantially all of our assets are transferred to another company, or as part of a bankruptcy proceeding, we may transfer the information we have collected from you to the other company. In this case, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.
  * **_In Response to Legal Process._** We also may disclose the information we collect from you in order to comply with the law, a judicial proceeding, court order, or other legal process, such as in response to a court order or a subpoena.
  * **_To Protect Us and Others._** We also may disclose the information we collect from you where we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person, violations of our Terms of Use or this Policy, or as evidence in litigation in which Rewarder is involved.
  * **_Aggregate and De-Identified Information._** We may share aggregate or de-identified information about users with third parties for marketing, advertising, research, or similar purposes.

**Our Use of Cookies and Other Tracking Mechanisms**

We use cookies, web beacons, java script, widgets and other tracking mechanisms to track information about your use of our Site, App, or Services. We may combine this information with other personal information we collect from you.

**_Cookies._** Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer's hard drive through your web browser for record-keeping purposes. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. We link the information we store in cookies to any personal information you submit while on our site. Some cookies allow us to make it easier for you to navigate our Site and Services, while others are used to enable a faster log-in process or to allow us to track your activities at our Site and while using our Services. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but if you prefer, you can edit your browser options to block them in the future. The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your computer from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. Visitors to our Site who disable cookies will be able to browse certain areas of the Site, but some features may not function.

**_Clear GIFs, pixel tags and other technologies._** Clear GIFs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on your computer's hard drive, clear GIFs are embedded invisibly on web pages. We may use clear GIFs (a.k.a. web beacons, web bugs or pixel tags), in connection with our Site to, among other things, track the activities of Site visitors, help us manage content, and compile statistics about Site usage. We and our third-party service providers also use clear GIFs in HTML emails to our customers, to help us track email response rates, identify when our emails are viewed, and track whether our emails are forwarded. We tie the information gathered to your personal information.

**_Widgets._** Our Web site includes Widgets, which are interactive mini-programs that run on our site to provide specific services from another company (e.g. displaying the news, opinions, music, etc.). Personal information, such as your email address, may be collected through the Widget. Cookies may also be set by the Widget to enable it to function properly. Information collected by this Widget is governed by the privacy policy of the company that created it.

**Third-Party Analytics**

**Third-Party Analytics and Tracking.** We use automated devices and applications, such as Google Analytics, to evaluate usage of our Site and, to the extent permitted, our App. We also may use other analytic means to evaluate our Services. We use these tools to help us improve our Services, performance and user experiences. These entities may use cookies and other tracking technologies to perform their services, and may combine the information they collect about you on our Site with the information they have collected about you on other, third party sites. We do not share your personal information with these third parties. We do not link this automatically-collected data to any of your personal information.

**Ad Networks**

We use third parties, such as network advertisers, to display advertisements on third party sites. Network advertisers are third parties that display advertisements based on your use of our Site and other third party sites (which is often referred to as "retargeting"). This enables us and these third parties to target advertisements by displaying ads for products and services in which you might be interested. Third-party ad network providers, advertisers, sponsors, and/or traffic measurement services may use cookies, JavaScript, web beacons (including clear GIFs), Flash LSOs, and other technologies to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize advertising content to you. These third-party cookies and other technologies are governed by each third party's specific privacy policy, not this one. We may provide these third-party advertisers with information about your usage of our Site and our Services, as well as aggregate or non-personally identifiable information about visitors to our Site and users of our service; however, we do share personally identifiable information about users with them.

Currently, our Site does not honor browser requests not to be tracked. You may, however, opt out of many third-party ad networks, including those operated by members of the Network Advertising Initiative ("NAI") and the Digital Advertising Alliance ("DAA"). For more information regarding this practice by NAI members and DAA members, and your choices regarding having this information used by these companies, including how to opt-out of third-party ad networks operated by NAI and DAA members, please visit their respective websites: [www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp](http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp) (NAI) and [www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices) (DAA).

Opting out of one or more NAI member or DAA member networks (many of which will be the same) only means that those members no longer will deliver targeted content or ads to you. It does not mean you will no longer receive any targeted content or ads on our Site or other websites. You may continue to receive advertisements, for example, based on the particular website that you are viewing. Also, if your browsers are configured to reject cookies when you visit this opt-out page, or you subsequently erase your cookies, use a different computer or change web browsers, your NAI or DAA opt-out may no longer be effective. Additional information is available on NAI and DAA websites accessible by the above links.

**User-Generated Content**

We invite you to post content on our Site or in our App, including your comments, pictures, and any other information that you would like to be available on our Site. If you post content, all of the information that you post will be available to all visitors to our Site and users of our App. If you post your own content, your posting may become public and Rewarder cannot prevent such information from being used in a manner that may violate this Policy, the law, or your personal privacy. Our blog is managed by a third party application that may require you to register or log in to post a comment. You will need to contact or login into the third party application if you want the personal information that was posted to the comments section removed. _To learn how the third party application uses your information, please review their privacy policy._

We may also display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [info@rewarder.com](mailto:info@rewarder.com).

**Third-Party Links**

Our Site, App, and Services may contain links to third-party websites. Any access to and use of such linked websites is not governed by this Policy, but instead is governed by the privacy policies of those third-party websites. We are not responsible for the information practices of such third-party websites.

**Security of My Personal Information**

We have implemented commercially reasonable precautions to protect the personal information we collect from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on our order forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). Please be aware that despite our best efforts, no data security measures can guarantee 100% security. You should take steps to protect against unauthorized access to your password, phone, and computer by, among other things, signing off after using a shared computer, choosing a robust password that nobody else knows or can easily guess, and keeping your log-in and password private. We are not responsible for any lost, stolen, or compromised passwords or for any activity on your account via unauthorized password activity. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us at [info@rewarder.com](mailto:info@rewarder.com).

**Access To My Personal Information**

You may modify or delete the profile information that you have submitted by logging into your account and updating your profile information. Please note that copies of information that you have updated, modified or deleted may remain viewable in cached and archived pages of the Site or App for a period of time.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**Marketing Communications**

We may send periodic promotional or informational emails to you. You may opt out of such communications by following the opt-out instructions contained in the email. Please note that it may take up to 10 business days for us to process opt-out requests. If you opt out of receiving emails about recommendations or other information we think may interest you, we may still send you emails about your account or any Services you have requested or received from us.

**Children Under 13**

Our Services are not designed for children under 13. If we discover that a child under 13 has provided us with personal information, we will delete such information from our systems.

**Changes to this Policy**

This Policy is current as of the Effective Date set forth above. We may change this Policy from time to time, so please be sure to check back periodically. We will post any changes to this Policy on our Site, at [**http://www.rewarder.com/privacy**](http://www.rewarder.com/privacy), and in our App. If we make any changes to this Policy that materially affect our practices with regard to the personal information we have previously collected from you, we will endeavor to provide you with notice in advance of such change by highlighting the change on our Site, or by emailing you at your email address of record.

**Contact Us**

If you have questions about the privacy aspects of our Services or would like to make a complaint, please contact us at [info@rewarder.com](mailto:info@rewarder.com) or through our mailing address below:

Rewarder, Inc.  
564 Market Street, Suite 705  
San Francisco, CA 94104
